well we're back and we have an exciting
show today we're doing a fun live recipe
demo with Lena
she's a part of the ultimate raw vegan
bundle and going to be joining us pretty
quickly she has an amazing new Next
Level pasta book that's a part of the
ultimate raw vegan bundle but somehow
she fandangled me into making one of my
most for my Cravings Busters book and
we're gonna bring it to you live
together and maybe some of you have uh
got all the ingredients and are gonna
make it with us it's really fun it's
this what is it huh it's a tie stew yeah
that's what we're making making a ties
to both of us have our books a part of
the ultimate raw vegan bundle 40 books
50 bucks it's worth 1850 bucks so it's
like 96 off and it's only here until 11
59 PST near midnight on Thursday the
11th so now's the time to do that deal I
recommend you go get it in Lena's
profile or mine if you'd like and uh you
stay tuned for this recipe demo hello
hello welcome welcome how are you guys
doing let's invite Lena in here and get
crack and
oh welcome there's gonna be lots of fun
apologies for the light my battery for
my ring light turned off so I need this
one otherwise I'm going to get really
dark in here so
here we go working hey how you doing hi
I'm great good to see you yeah nice
perfectly on well okay I'm a little bit
tardy because all of a sudden my phone I
realized is gonna die during the live so
I had to scramble and get a power cord
okay but now you're good I should be
good I just don't have a light because
normally I have this fancy Dancy battery
that of course had my stickers on it and
I use it to charge my ring light and my
phone but for some reason it stopped
charging and even though I've been
charging it for a few hours it's not
working so thus the scramble and the
partial Darkness I'm not trying to hide
any like hideous uh issues or something
you know what we have exactly we just do
it we just do what we can so I I think
I'm a little bit dark as well but I put
the light on it's even
though yeah then we look all shiny and
crazy and it's like yes no bueno we
don't want that that going on the how
are things going on over there and for
everyone here who doesn't know you where
are you at and can you tell us a little
bit about yourself yes
so I'm from Germany I'm in Nuremberg
right now it's in Bavaria
and
um I'm actually a ballet dancer so this
was my my job for many years I teach
ballet class
and now I'm also a certified
nutritionist nice so I coach people with
the raw vegan lifestyle because myself I
mean for me it was just game changing so
I need to put it out there I think
that's what we all feel if because we
are so passionate and we just want to
share it it's so important absolutely
yeah I think it's one of the most common
things with people who get into this
lifestyle is that they just like feel so
enamored so emblazed and so passion
driven they just want to share it like
you can't help but share a feeling
that's good right yeah you have to share
it so yeah
and I was also able to reverse some
health issues like I had severe gut
issues skin problems and
osteoporosis actually yikes yeah that's
intense especially when you're doing
ballet and stuff you don't want to have
that going on yeah some rope and broken
ribs
increasing so yeah I'm really happy
that's awesome that's awesome is this
something that you've helped other
ballet dancers with as well and and
shared this message towards them at all
or oh not so much in the ballet movement
it's not no I'm working with people
outside the ballet world I would say
yeah yeah it's unfortunate I would think
within ballet and modeling there would
be a strong prevalence of potentially
eating disorders and um yeah low body
weight and low self image and stuff like
that it was like a competition who is
the skinniest and yeah
yeah it's really tough to hear really
tough to hear but this message is
spreading the more of us doing it uh
from different Vantage points and with
different backgrounds the more people is
going to connect with and seeds are
being planted that's for sure yeah
that's for sure so before we get into
this delicious recipe because I know we
both pre-prepped and we have stuff kind
of like hidden back here and stuff like
that
um
no one can see yet
um I wanted to go into your book a
little bit because your book is amazing
your next level pastas that's going
through it there's a bunch I would
really like to try I really like the uh
is it candle cat what are the round ones
yeah
yes
there's a whole bunch that look
delicious but that was like oh that's
really unique and very cool too yeah
this was it happened uh by accident
actually yeah I had a wrap and I rolled
it up without any filling and just ate
it with my salad and then I thought if I
cut it it looks like pen and noodles so
yeah yeah it looks beautiful they have
lots of delicious recipes in there do
you have any favorites that if that
one's your paper do you have any others
that are favorites
[Music]
um
that's a hard question
yeah the goggles solar cheese because I
not only have pasta recipes I also have
some bonus recipes like cheese different
cheeses and toppings and sauces
dressings and you can also use it as a
topping for salad bowls or something
yeah and the Gorgonzola cheese is with
cashews and with spirulina powder to
create the texture and the color and
somehow it's really the flavor is really
unique we have the spirulina and the
cashews and
um with cultures living cultures so yeah
it's high fat but you really you just
need a little bit and it's already great
on salads so yeah so you don't need to
have just a bowl of that you can have it
on top of other stuff of course you
don't eat the whole cheese in one
sitting yeah you hope not anyway right
or at least definitely not every day
maybe on an odd occasion it could happen
but not every day not every day okay
once a year and then your fat is covered
for the whole year yeah
oh that's way too fun that's way too fun
so have you ever heard of noodilitarians
would you consider yourself a big noodle
person like some people they just they
aim to just eat noodles yeah that's the
thing because if I talk to people and I
tell them that I only eat raw fruits and
vegetables the first thing they always
tell me is oh I could not do this
because I love my pasta yeah
and that's yeah that's why I created
this book
because you you don't have to cut it out
you you can't eat pasta still yeah and
it's even better because you feel
still great afterwards not not tired and
sluggish I like to eat both this big and
still feel amazing yeah
correct Bowl here
that's a that's a nice one that's a
pretty Bowl Mike I do have a fun bowl
back here for the stew but I think it's
a little big for the stew because the
stews kind of go like this you know but
I have one big important question for
you and just gonna kind of put you on
the spot and if you don't feel
comfortable with it it's fine but um no
I'm nervous yeah yeah I'm sorry to bring
it up but I've been thinking about it
for a while
um if you had to pick are you a zoodle
person or a coodle person
there we go all right and if anyone
doesn't know cuddles are cucumber
noodles and zoodles are zucchini noodles
and I sometimes like to make uh nap
poodles snap poodles just nap a cabbage
noodles a slice snap a cabbage thing
that's like my super lazy noodle okay I
never did that yeah poodles yeah that's
the first time I've said the word and
I'll I'll try and coin it you know not
poodles I would say it also depends on
the sauce
yes sometimes I like
a few common noodles with different
sauces and yeah it depends but generally
speaking so if you're not talking with
that then so
with cucumber noodles do you like
thicker sauces or or thinner and with
zucchini vice versa you have you figured
that out is there like one that holds
certain sauces better you think
with cucumber noodles maybe more denser
sauces yeah maybe with hemp seeds or
yeah some seeds or nuts and with
zucchini noodles they are already a
little bit
thika and small satiating I would say
yeah so it goes well with tomato mango
yeah I feel the exact same way
I'm just I'm just teasing I'm sorry I'm
a silly man I'm a silly man uh well do
you want to get into this or is there
anything else you'd like to go into no
no I I have my coconut milk and I put it
into the freezer because we made your
recipe with Julia last week and we just
made more so I don't have to make it
twice
um I hope it's it's good I put it out
this morning it should be should be good
good deal well I mean the good thing is
even if it isn't good we'll both just
smile a whole bunch and everyone will
believe it is and they'll never know
let's start
I have I have my messy coconut milk in
here too and just made it fresh well
yeah I just made it a little bit a
little bit ago here but
um just so everyone knows we did this
because it is a bit of a pain in the
butt and takes a little bit of a time a
little bit of time to make some fresh
coconut milk and the simplest it's so
worth it because the flavor is so
intense compared to like the canned ones
yeah
and to me it's like classic classic
curries they have this mature coconut
coconutty flavor because you know you
could make fresh coconut milk for sure
out of young Thai coconut and just
blending the water with a bit of the
jelly and it makes a fine sweet sweet
kind of uh I find often a little bit
more desserty but it can be really great
in any Thai Dish as well
um but these mature ones I just love
that deep deep coconut flavor you know
and yeah
um and for me it's difficult to catch
the young coconuts here in Germany I can
almost not find them maybe sometimes in
the Asian store but yeah really
difficult yeah here I have a pretty hard
time getting both to be honest I see
them on occasion and we just actually
saw like cases of brown coconuts the
other day didn't get a whole case
because I didn't think I'd go through
all of them you know but
um but just so people know too it's
really simple to make your own coconut
milk
um I have the recipe in my book I have a
video actually it's a link to a video
that really goes in depth on it but the
simplest way to say it is you take one
of those brown mature coconuts you pop
the top open I usually use a corkscrew
or a nail or something and get it open
on top pour the water in there and then
you bash the shell and take all the the
white parts off the shell put it in the
blender and blend it with just enough
water to cover blend it super super
smooth and then do it can you see that
oh yeah I got my my nut milk bag back
here drying just pour it into a nut milk
bag
and if you don't have a nut milk bag I
mean you could use a brand new sock you
know if you want or you could use like
pan you could use pantyhose for like one
time I used this I'll admit I used that
when I couldn't find my nut milk bag you
just put it in there
sorry
um it worked out or not oh yeah I mean
you could you clean t-shirt I mean it's
just a sieve right and just squeeze it I
just want to make sure it's really clean
but it's not milk bags inexpensive and
really nice and um you squeeze it out
you get the milk and if you can't find
if you can't find mature coconuts you
can also get the dried coconut like
flakes in the store and just soak them
overnight or soak them for quite a while
do the same thing blend it all up really
smooth and you can seave it out it's not
quite as Rich of a flavor because some
of the oils have dissipated and stuff
like that but um it still works and I
mean otherwise you could just use like
you know your favorite seed or nut and
blend it with a little bit of water into
like a creamy nut milk right but to make
this classic we're talking coconut milk
right
the pop afterwards for
something not always a lot of time most
of the time I just compost it to be
honest I'm I'm a little bit wasteful
sometimes
do you like to use it
not really the flavor is kind of gone
dressings or yeah just make peas I don't
know but yeah right now I don't have the
time in um in a lot of countries where
they grow they often have a first
pressing and a second pressing and the
first pressing of the milk when you when
you pull the the liquid out it's the
fattiest creamiest and that's usually
used more for uh
um like thick curries and desserts and
stuff like that and then the thinner
stuff is more kind of soupy and a little
bit less flavorful and they still use it
but it's just you know used for
different purposes
yeah
but I usually just use the first one
myself and sometimes I've used other
stuff for other things but kind of lazy
so how do you want to do this do you
want do you want to should we call out
ingredients you want to call it
ingredients what should we do here
I'm so confusing
you guide us oh guys
you are the
yeah
I'll be the guider I'll I'll take the
role as the stew Master today oh you're
okay here let's see I'll get this down
and surprise there's some ingredients
there hopefully it will stay
oh there we go okay and then I'll get
back over here
so in here we already have like a cup of
coconut milk right so that's gonna be
the very base of the sauce so we can
have that in the blender
and then for the chunky bits because to
me what makes us do my sweet and savory
stews Cravings Busters is chunky bits
with a nice thick sauce and I kind of
tried to make these so that it's almost
like a giant salad condensed down you
know a lot of salad ingredients and some
stews are a little bit richer and
thicker and have more greens and stuff
like that pulsed in this is a lighter
kind of more juicy and summery stew you
know that is nice could be lunch could
be before dinner could be dinner right
but uh we have a bunch of really nice
juicy stuff so
sorry can I ask you
a question why why is it called Curry if
that's
good
hopefully you're still there yes I'm
here it's funny what popped up on the
screen on the screen did something go
wrong I've never seen that before
but I knew I was asking for trouble when
I straddled my power cord I was like
that wasn't a good call
well you know interestingly there are a
lot of um Thai curries that don't really
use curry powder they just use the curry
kind of flavors like sometimes they'll
use like Lime Leaf and ginger and stuff
like that so and when I made this book
too I wanted to be cognant of the
difference between kind of real
traditional traditional curries like
Rich curries and more stew-like curries
because otherwise I could easily start
just turning the stew book into a curry
book and I wanted to make sure that it
was a little more stew-like so
looking at it I I could have not said
Curry could have been like raw Thai stew
and yeah maybe I'll actually update that
because I noticed a couple other things
even in this recipe I noticed that the
cilantro forgot to have the weight in
pounds it just says grams so I have to
do a couple little team updates
yeah
the brain melted when I was finishing
making this book I tell you
was it yeah was it quite a process
making your pasta book yeah
yeah
I'm sorry about that
so we have here let's see if I can do it
so in the recipe we have
um you know about uh near a pound like
345 grams or 0.75 pounds of tomatoes and
half of those Tomatoes will go in the
blender and half of those Tomatoes will
go chunky in the bowl
are you ready for it ready
[Music]
this one okay that one can go right into
the the blender then and I'll do the
same I'll put um
half of the tomatoes I kind of chopped
up half Big And Chunky two to go in
there with the with the coconut milk
and I'll put that right into the blender
and
the other half I'm going to put in this
big giant Super Bowl for the chunky
portion of the stew along with 230 grams
or one half a pound of cubed cucumbers
as well now
how big you like to cube things in dice
things oh beautiful well we even peeled
yours yours looks really nice sometimes
I prefer without peel sometimes I leave
it on but this was not an organic one so
I thought yeah better peeling it nice
that's awesome I was pretty lucky I got
some local local Svenska cucumbers over
here and they're really they're actually
gurkas they're the little ones they're
really really nice
crunchy yeah exactly I love those so
much
so we got those mixed in there and then
we took about a half a pineapple and uh
half of that pineapple is gonna go into
the blender
give a nice kind of sweet and a little
bit of a punch kind of flavor to it
I never had pineapple in a Savory dish
so it's the first time
they're fun I like to have them in some
curries and in Pizza those are usually
the two places that I enjoyed in Savory
dishes
and I tell you a lot of people they say
like oh like pizza like pineapple and
pizza is illegal you shouldn't do it
put in raw pizzas I find that it like it
just actually makes it sometimes because
it adds just a little you know sweetness
do you use it as a topping on the pizza
or in the dough yeah usually use the
topping and I usually kind of cut it
into little wedges and then have it on
top so that it slightly dehydrates and
gets a little bit extra sweet and I
don't know there's something magic about
it it's just like it rounds the flavor I
think
raw Pizza it's a common thing I think
absolutely
yeah and a funny fact about that is
Hawaiian pizza was actually invented in
Canada
oh really yeah they just they called it
Hawaiian because uh you know pineapples
are calm into Hawaii and pigs they do a
lot of hog hunting and stuff so uh so
they just named it that but it came from
Canada it was so weird right that's
weird yeah yeah
little things that stick in my brain
that really aren't that important but
the important stuff usually just flies
away
[Music]
so we have the other half of the
pineapple which is about 115 grams ish I
mean it doesn't have to be exact but uh
you know just playing with these these
amounts and comparison
it's for one person like me
actually you know it's kind of funny to
be honest these recipes I find the
portions are like a a pretty decently
large portion for the average person you
know for some people they might want to
cut them in half and have it as two
portions and then for some people they
might want to double it if they're like
really a big big appetite because I for
me this is a comfortable portion but if
I was going to have this for dinner I
would for sure have a big fruit meal to
start you know I could eat as much
smoothie or anything else and then I'd
be perfect but if I was just eating this
I'd probably eat like 1.5 and some
hungry days I might even eat double yeah
yummy because I also start with food
always yeah it's such a good tip you
know a lot of people miss that and in my
Consulting practice it's one of the most
common things that really can help
people get more calories easily and
avoid feeling the need to binge on fat
at the end of the night or eat past or
digestive comfort and it's as simple as
you know when you start your dinner meal
or anytime you're hungry starting with
fruit and eating it until you're totally
satiated and then go into your Savory
fix and it just like it really helps so
much do you do you find the same yes
and then I yeah it's a shame then for
shame
we live we learn well I mean it's so
classic right like that's how most
people treat root as a dessert and uh
and then often they blame just they
blame the fruit I'm still upset stomachs
and stuff like that but yeah but since I
changed that
it's like day and night difference I
love it I love it and and you know a
kind of funny caveat on that too if
that's the accurate word I'm kind of
just throwing that out there because I
like that word but
sometimes I have consulted someone who
they ate fruit for dinner like before
their dinner but let's say they're
having something like this that has a
pineapple and uh you know bell peppers
and tomatoes all this acid fruit and
they're oh yeah Michelle Diamond helps
what's up homie um and what they did
though instead of having something juicy
say something like orange or melon or
you know pineapple before mango they had
a big banana smoothie to start their
dinner and then had a big salad and we
didn't catch it for a while like you
know a couple months they started
getting like sour stomach and some
digestive issues and finally figured out
that it was bananas that they're eating
before I didn't even think of it because
to me it doesn't that doesn't appeal to
have bananas before these flavors but
maybe it's just because food combining
is so ingrained in like my damn head
I also kind of
nope oh
I'm sorry
I have actually done completely on its
own I'm sorry yeah I'll be here I'm
melon for me goes really well
um before anything and actually better
if I mix it with Citrus I I find
watermelon or any or any sweet melon
goes incredibly good with lemon lime and
citrus and in my practice most the time
I find that people find that works
really really well but have you ever
tried like watermelon orange before no
as a movie or just squeeze on it either
both like um for me watermelon with
lemon lime orange or pineapple squeezed
on top way better flavor for me I'm not
a huge watermelon person but I like it
even more and I find it digests better
and it actually can help prevent melon
belly
um but one of my favorite smoothies is
like orange juice and watermelon
combined half and half and I know um you
know that in classic food combining
guides it says melon must be must be
eaten alone but through experimentation
and sorry
for me I mean I never tried this thing I
will try this yeah yeah give it a go and
let me know because I find like I mean
I've been studying food combining since
99 and I used to think it think of it as
a law like I couldn't break it
um but then through experimentation and
talking with others you know like Doug
Graham and others who've been doing this
a long time found that some of those
tenants they aren't really scientific
and it's interesting because food
combining was actually first created as
a way of weight loss it wasn't meant for
Digestive chemistry and some of those
tenants you know they were put together
and not necessarily against scientific
or super well researched and what what I
found to be a really simplified way of
looking at it is the foods that are
similar water content often like the
fruits they're similar water content
often digest really well together
because they have similar transit times
and juicy Citrus and melon they're
pretty darn close and for me there is
something magic about uh the Citrus of
melon because if you've ever experienced
melon belly eating watermelon and having
that stomach pain for me it's also had
you cannot describe it no it like it can
feel like your spine's on fire and
my sister once she chugged two two
liters of watermelon smoothie and fell
on the ground in fetal position and was
like she thought she was gonna die and
some super easy tips just in case anyone
has had that experience
um one you know eat it a little slower
you know two make sure that you're well
hydrated and sounds counter-intuitive
but if we're dehydrating we eat melon it
can actually be a little bit hard on our
sugar absorption because it's really
really fast absorbing
um three
um what's it called get some exercise
before so you create demand for it so it
can your body can uptake it really well
four I find squeezing lemon lime
pineapple on it actually really helps a
lot and five
um doctor not doctor Don Bennett he has
found that if people are low in chromium
they actually have a harder time uh
assimilating fruit sugar really quickly
from foods like melon or mango or grapes
and they can get that same sensation but
when they top up their chromium then
they actually have more efficient sugar
metabolism and that problem goes away so
four good tips yeah thank you
it's a it's a it's such a painful thing
every time it comes up I have to share
because I don't want anyone else to
experience that you know to the point
where they're curled up and crying and
saying blast those melons I can't eat
them
so back on track one bell pepper um it's
actually this one was what I have a bell
pepper but it's about 115 grams or about
a quarter of a pound yeah
and
then this actually looks like a lot to
me but because these ingredients are
still sweet and delicious it can go well
I have um about 50 grams of onion
half white onion that's okay
oh gosh
um
I think we should probably close this
food demo down I feel some Discord in
our onion color
but it wasn't Us in the recipe it only
wrote down
you're tough you're tough you've just
stuck it to me I love it um yeah of
course every onion is great
um
how should I know you know what you're
I'm just the one being the jackass to be
very honest it doesn't say and probably
yellow or white onion especially like
sweet Maui onion that would be amazing
that'd probably be perfect but any onion
will do this is actually just the onions
that I happen to have
but um what do you have there is that oh
that's your onion hey okay there we go
so a little trick with onions
a red one also
also cut it
everyone just wants to pause the video
we'll just wait until Lena cuts the
night practice I'm totally just joking
no we're not going to do that any color
bombing is great
um some people like spicier onions some
people like mild onions some people like
sweeter onions I I like these ones I
like sweet ones I like white ones but if
you're sensitive to onion if you cut it
and let it sit for half an hour it makes
it a little bit milder and less
irritating on the digestive tract so I
cut these and we'll just put those in
there
um
I talk a lot don't I
I get kind of bossy when I'm in the
kitchen I'm sorry
so that's that's really all the the mixy
chunky stuff and if you want you can uh
you know find like a Golden Spoon or
whatever you like and you know mix it
all up and get those flavors mingling
and
you give it a little sniff oh my gosh it
smells so dang good together I tell you
you have a grown spoon actually at home
oh yes
do you have a gold food yes
it looks pretty gold or is it kind of
more brassy yeah
that's fun
well I I secretly really hope your
pineapple is sweeter than mine because I
went to four shops today to find a
pineapple and all of them were pretty
but it's not really ripe but I couldn't
find a better one so yeah well I'll edit
this part out we'll smile big and just
pretend it was amazing
so we got that and then we have our our
coconut milk and all those other
ingredients and to that we are going to
add these are some fancy ingredients
about 15 grams ish or uh what did I say
a quarter cup of sun-dried tomatoes
about the same amount about you know 15
grams or a quarter cup of dry pineapple
did you find dried pineapple yes oh it's
not homemade so I bought it nice nice I
think mine's a mix of homemade and
bought okay
um put that in there
and then I said a uh what I say a
tablespoon I think
a tablespoon of Ginger which I mean
maybe Ginger to your flavor
yeah
both both are good for sure
but I just throw that in there because
I'm pretty damn lazy
and a little bit though with the ginger
because I ruined my dressing a few days
days ago I put too much Ginger and then
I had to throw it away because it was
not a tribal Well what we'll try and do
here is uh we'll go with the recipe and
then afterwards if you throw it away you
can tell me privately but um otherwise
let's just pretend it's really good no
matter what
here a teaspoon of um powdered garlic
you could use fresh garlic if you like I
I like both sometimes but I find the
powdered garlic has a little bit uh
a little bit more of a kind of roasty
flavor and it's a little less kind of
irritating to me and um also when you
blend it like because I like to blend
this because there's the really dried
ingredients I want to blend it really
smooth and you can over blend garlic and
it goes bitter so if you're using fresh
garlic add it after you've Blended all
the hard bits and then add it kind of a
little bit later yeah that's also true
for some herbs
absolutely
yeah absolutely and we're going to be
using one of those herbs
cilantro mint and basic
Ally but not yet not yet blow your role
all right by the way is it um herbs or
herbs
I don't know okay
I don't know all right so we have lime
juice and what did I say there I said
one tablespoon about one lime
the lime and ginger really can be to
taste right so but it's too late for you
you've already added all the ginger so
it's that's just how it's going to be
yeah
I'm just gonna squeeze this in here
Nuremberg I think I think I was in
Nuremberg last year
last year
yeah
I think so
I went on a little bit of a Germany tour
I went to Berlin separately
skateboarding but then I also drove
through Germany and I think we went to
Nuremberg
what is this city that has the really
big giant like
um church that was like really like uh
fell apart and fell over and they
re-fixed it all up and it's like right
in the Town Center that's not Nuremberg
yeah maybe that's that I think I've been
to Nuremberg too
okay yeah we have also many churches
here yeah
yeah so many so much beautiful
architecture I love Europe the it's like
all this all the countries and all their
history and the architecture is amazing
so I'm going to add a little bit more of
this lime but I'm going to save a little
bit of lime on the side just to see if I
want a bit more at the end
um
no it's fine
all right and I think what we can
probably do is uh blend this up I don't
think there's
anything else except for the herbs or
herbs to add at the end
um
I'm gonna show off because I have my
fancy Dancy uh bioshack vacuum blender
top so I'm going to vacuum the heck out
of this
and
while this is blending um we can have a
blend dance or we can uh you know ear
muff or we can you know place your raids
if we want
okay what do you think dance or charades
which would you prefer
Dance all right down for dancing all
right you ready to blend I'm ready okay
you guys can vote after and see who's a
better dancer me of course I would I
would bet
oh yeah you're way better
my family is not giving you a dancing
oh God
oh well let's see
let's see how this is well that looks
pretty good it smells pretty good
it smells incredible oh wow all right so
to this now we can add
I'm a cilantro freak I could just eat
salads or cilantro I just love this
stuff I used to hate cilantro I really I
couldn't eat it it wasn't like
disgusting but now um I read the books
from Anthony William and he says that it
pulls out heavy metals yeah it does and
if you have lots of heavy metals then it
tastes like
really not good for you for your taste
buds and if you don't have heavy metals
then it tastes good but I don't know but
I also have that it's a genetic thing
yeah that's what I've heard more that
it's a genetic thing
um but you know I'd be I'd be really
interested to hear if anyone has found
that their flavors change because I've
never actually met anyone who has and
everything I've researched this is a
genetic thing so for me it changed I
mean it lasted four weeks or so and now
I really like it nice well there we go
maybe there is some truth to that that's
really cool yeah that's cool because
yeah cilantro is such a gift of a herb
and the the metal the heavy metal
pulling properties and stuff like that
whenever I hear someone say they don't
like it I do get a little bit of a tear
in my eye but I do Wonder In some cases
I wonder if both can be true because I
know that foods can affect our gene
expression so I wonder if you know heavy
metal detox and eating foods and stuff
like that eating Fresh Foods can change
that expression of the gene that affects
the Taste of cilantro and who knows
that's something that's something neat
to research that's pretty cool
so I have here about
um just about 15 grams of cilantro kind
of like a handful yeah I'm just gonna
block that in there and the recipe said
10 leaves of basil and 10 leaves of mint
you know a couple grams of each but you
can really use as much or as little as
you want I got this fresh organic basil
and mint in the background
and um
I'm gonna
get that and if you're a fancy Dancy one
you know sometimes I feel fancy Dancy
you can instead just uh really thinly
slice the basil and pop those little
teeny basil slices on top instead of
pulsing it
sometimes I feel fancy and sometimes I'm
just like a a lazy Leo you know just
wanted to just relax and have it come to
me me too
are you a Leo yourself
are you a Leo no
I'm a twin
sorry a twin I'm a trip oh oh Gemini
yeah yeah there you go twins
that's cool
oh I gotta be careful I'm getting
here in my my herbs I don't want any
hair in my herbs
oh I like this one all right so we got
all of this this fresh herbage in there
and if you don't have fresh you can of
course use uh dried as well but
something something's nice about fresh
herbs you know fresh is always the best
all right so I'm just going to pulse
this a bit we don't want to turn it into
a green sauce we still want little teeny
chunks so just just pulsing it so that
we uh get it well mixed in okay go here
we go
there we go I don't know why but I
really enjoy doing that like that boom
boom boom you know that's so fun I like
it is
oh
all right I have one leaf like one leaf
just clung to the side of the blender
like nope I'm not going in
This Is The Moment of Truth
are you ready for it should we do it
all right
I'm just gonna pull oh gosh can you see
what's going on here guys I'm curious is
anyone making this with us or are we
alone in this world
I need to put it down so I can do the
same thing as you we were twice as
clever
foreign
I'm getting hungry I'm damn excited that
this live worked out so perfectly for us
at dinner time you know
perfect so I have a food demo
on the last day but it's 2 p.m PST but
for me it's 11 p.m and I'm making like a
hearty stew at 11 p.m at night
and I'm gonna eat it I'll tell you but
it's gonna be a late dinner and I
probably will you know regret it the
next day but I'll enjoy it while I'm
eating it I cannot eat salads my sleep
is not good
no I'm kind of like a tank I can get
away with a law to tell you
I mean not that I would ever try and get
away with a lot you know I
I'm a good kid okay
all right
mixing it up mixing it up so now we
spread it on a dehydrator tray at 350
for 45 minutes
no I'm joking we don't do that but you
could warm it up a little bit Yeah you
absolutely could you totally could you
could uh you could spread it and warm it
or you could put it in a uh what's it
called an additional dehydrator for a
while but yeah
but here we go what do you think should
we try it you guys had this the other
day or did you have a different one
here's this one no no a different one
yeah the Jamaican
delicious
piece of pineapple because I never had
pineapple and I'll save every dish
right
yeah let's go for it I'm just gonna
watch you
um
10 out of 10.
I like the mint pineapple coconuts
combination
mint and pineapple is always always
great
it's funny
did you get these up there I wonder
where's this from
you ever you had this brand out there no
no the only brand out here that's like
legit raw juice
it even says on it
raw for real
oh okay pretty cool but I had this for
um breakfast today and it's Apple
pineapple lime Ginger and mint and it's
so good yeah I have
finches or pineapple fashion fruit juice
every morning it's so good yeah that
sounds ridiculous I like it as a pre
work out
all the lunch before I go to ballet
class
so I like to have liquids only in the
morning
and yeah pineapple juice is perfect
I can identify because when I skateboard
or if I go to the gym I don't like to
have a big full belly and be burping
while I'm doing it it takes away from
the experience
and then afterwards
afterwards yeah yeah powering up
afterwards yeah yeah
no
not good so I don't think I will either
and um I hope that my friend Michelle
who's watching isn't expecting to eat
dinner with me
because he's watching he's going to come
over he just lives a block away okay but
I think I'm gonna eat I'm gonna eat this
to myself yeah Troy Michelle
yeah exactly
it's all good though
I wanted to check here in the chat has
anyone here made this with us today
you do want some Michelle yeah he says
he does okay I'll save some for you
I'll save some for you
yeah I like a ninja caught a piece of
the fellow in my mouth
[Music]
let's see I'm just gonna double check
real quick about 12 40 p.m here wow geez
I feel very hungry I'm on the bus on the
way home so I guess probably didn't make
it with us
um there's a question about your temper
on the Vitamix
yes it is um where is it
my tamper is actually over here
and
this Vitamix is uh
one of the newer ones the ascent 3500
and it's a shorter container so it has a
specific tamper so yeah so it's a little
bit bulbous and weird but it it works
and that's one of my favorite things
about the Vitamix for certain recipes to
be able to jam in stuff to the blades
and make the thickest curries or sauces
or ice creams or whatever you want to do
what's that the vacuum thing is this for
the Vitamix or do we have another
blender yeah so the the biochef isn't
designed for the the new Vitamix but the
new Vitamix does have a gasket around
the top which actually seals a lot
better so it makes an air type seal and
I I did kind of Jerry rig this I I glued
a bottle cap from one of those juice
bottles on the bottom with some little
slits on the side so that when I put it
on top it fits perfectly and it works
perfectly but without this
um it might splash some of the juice
into the the suction part right into the
bathroom I could not use it on this
is that the one that one has the regular
rubber lid right
so you can you can use those Lids I
actually have a video on how to turn
that into a vacuum blender as well
but it doesn't create quite as good of a
seal so it so I've experienced some
blenders it works a little better in
some it doesn't work quite as well and I
needed to create like a special top out
of a bathtub stop in order to create
nice seal on the top and then just get a
hand pump so I do have a video on how to
it says I think it's just called like
how to turn your Vitamix into a vacuum
blender it's on my YouTube channel so
you can do with that yeah
you'll notice some difference it does
work but it's not quite as good as this
or if you get like a dedicated vacuum
blender
But but so you know I actually bought
this together
with this which looks like a regular
vacuum or regular Vitamix container but
this is actually a biochef container mix
that is made for Vitamix and this one
has a special lid that this fits on
perfectly on top and it works amazing
but it's about 170 bucks or like like
you know around the same price probably
in Euros but it is fun and it will fit
on any Vitamix but the funny thing is
the new vitamixes they have some neat
kind of like Wireless connectivity and
these containers won't work on here so
if I put it on there it's like nope
wrong container and it won't even work
so
luckily this worked because when I got
this new Vitamix that was the one thing
I was thinking I'm like okay I'm gonna
have to come up with a new way to turn
this into a vacuum blender but luckily
this just seriously plopped right on top
and it's like awesome you know
okay cool do you notice a huge
difference
yeah you know I do but it's not like
it's not like a I wouldn't drink
smoothies without it it's not like that
profound of a difference or that when I
drink smoothies without it I'm like sad
and thinking less to myself at all you
know but it does increase
um the antioxidant value or rather it
retains more of the antioxidant value
because the air isn't being whipped in
um it amazingly makes more of like a wet
tasting drink smoothie sauce like
there's less air whipped in right so
it's just it's it's more condensed and
it is more of colorful flavorful and it
doesn't separate as easily and it keeps
better because it has a higher
antioxidant value so it makes a pretty
big difference I actually have a good
video also on my channel compare
comparing a Vitamix without a vacuum
blender to a vacuum blender and I make a
whole bunch of dishes and I tried them
side by side and I even let them sit on
the counter for like an hour to see how
fast they separate and it makes it makes
a pretty darn big difference and that's
why I still use this even though I'm
using the the Vitamix okay cool if I
keep on trying to poke Vitamix or tell
them to make vacuum blenders themselves
and maybe one day they will
you're brave are you able to scroll up
and see all these comments too
oh be careful
one time I tried to scroll when I was a
guest on someone else's and kicked me
right out
and then I got a warning no I didn't get
a warning
a raw vegan 2021 thank you so much is
kind of you Michelle's saying dance and
many years experience herbs I don't know
what herbs do you know what is that a is
that a Swedish word or a German word
herb herbs
h-o-o-r-b-s how do you
well
herbs
I don't know
troops oh he's saying herbs I totally
didn't even know Michelle man what are
you doing good tips
awesome
rose gold spoon yeah that's true
watermelon with mint rub the T-shirt
Chris oh thank you this is a UK fruit
Fest fruit love t-shirt and uh Ronnie
Smith the creator of the UK fruit Fest
he is a part of the bundle as well and
he has an amazing book going into all
the festivals around the world of 2023
as well as goes into the history of
other group festivals from times past
with lots of pictures and stuff and it's
awesome and I guess it is fitting to
bring up the bundle again and mention
that we are both part of the bud Bill uh
with 40 contributors all together for
their brand new books and actually yes
it's a little more than 40 and that's
only available until 11 59 PST on the
11th 96 off it's a pretty ridiculous
deal isn't it
I kind of forgot I thought I thought
we're just hanging out here
you know people were watching I thought
we were just yeah I thought it was just
a chat
those are those are the best ones right
when we're just chilling out
always dessert first yeah yeah
Michelle's Michelle's representing here
pineapple on Pizza is fire
save a spoon for later okay yeah he did
he really does want the food well I I
just want to say thank you so much for
um for asking me to do this recipe
together I yeah
now yeah me too me too I'm ready for it
I'm ready for it do you have anything
else going on tonight do you have any
other lives today or tomorrow no today
not
no
Yep this is it for me tonight too I'm
gonna I think I'm gonna
just chill out for a bit eat some food
yeah awesome already it's sleep deprived
kind of yeah
I feel bad
yeah you only hear something that was
really silly
last night I was working until 4 AM
and then I woke up at nine
it wasn't wise this is this I don't
recommend this for health or for uh
smart Factor
yeah
it's not it's not enough but soon
we'll be able to sleep in more hey
thank you so much Chris such a pleasure
I I do want to ask uh is there anywhere
else anyone everyone can find you or oh
sure um you can find me at Lena
on YouTube too all right I'll make sure
to share that in the notes below and is
it all right with you if I load this up
on my YouTube channel as well yeah thank
you
all right sweet
all right well thank you so much Lena
and uh thanks everyone for joining us
and hopefully see you guys again enjoy
the bundle and hopefully see you
sometime in 3D yeah all right see you
guys bye